# Vincent Chow

Email: chowvk8@gmail.com

## Objective

Recent graduate with 4 years of experience of customer service within retail banking. Seeking to leverage strong analytical skills, programming proficiency, problem solving and a passion for technology to develop and excel in a technical position.

## **Education**

### Newcastle University BSc (Hons) Biology: First Class

Sept 2020 - July 2023

Modules include Computational Chemistry, Biological Modelling, Data

Visualisation in Ecology, Experimental Design and Statistics.

University of Liverpool BSc (Hons) Orthoptics: \*Unfinished

Sept 2017 – July 2019

Merchant Taylors' School Crosby (Sixth form)

Aug 2015 - May 2017

## **Skills**

- Programming Languages: Python, R, SQL
- Data Analytics: Data manipulation, visualisation, statistical analysis
- Tools: GitHub: chowvb (github.com), Git, VS Code, Jupyter.
- Problem Solving: Strong analytical and critical thinking abilities.
- Communication: Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Adaptability: Quick learner, open to new challenges and technologies.

# **Experience**

<u>Employer</u>	<u>Role</u>	
NatWest Group	Personal Banker	Oct 2023 - Dec 2024
	Oncall Personal Banker	Jun 2024 - Present
		Nov 2019 - Oct 2023

- Primarily work as a Cash Teller and Customer Service Whilst completing basic customer transactions, I must also be able to analyse transaction trends and quickly identify potential financial crime such as Money Laundering, Fraud, Scams.
- I'm the first point of call for technical queries involving the banking app and any computer/mobile application issues for both customers as well as staff.
- A keen eye for detail is required to find mistakes when balancing tills if there is a till discrepancy.
- Utilising NatWest's learning skills for the future to develop SQL skills and general programming skills.

Orthoptics Placement Student Orthoptics Sept 2017 - July 2019 (Ophthalmology)

 Spent 3 of the 9 months in the academic year on placement in different hospitals across the UK (Southport/Ormskirk, St Helens/Knowsley, Oldham and Kingston upon Hull)  By the end of my second year developed the communication, adaptability, critical thinking and confidence to lead my own triage clinic, testing patients and discussing treatment and management plans to treat different eye diseases.

#### Fortune Marine Café Waiter Jan 2015 - Dec 2020

- In the summer I managed the ice cream corner in the cafe where I was fully responsible for selling and stock taking while maintaining my normal position as a cashier and waiter.
- I interacted with customers, managed any complaints while building good customer relations which helped to develop my social and communication skills.

## **Projects**

# 1) University Research Project (Deep Learning: Object Detection/Image Classification)

- Developed a Deep Learning model using Python to automatically identify species
  of birds within camera trap images whilst filtering out blank images with no
  animals. Utilised object detection model (Megadetector) to locate animals in
  images. Cropped the images to the coordinates of the object detection bounding
  box to improve image classification accuracy during training and testing.
- Utilised Tensorflow with Keras, pandas, numpy, matplotlib, exifread.
- My model reduced processing time by 35 hours.
- Data Analytics and Visualisation completed in R, producing ordination plots using redundancy analysis.
- Aspects of my project (Deep learning) is to be incorporated into a MSc module at Newcastle University lead by Dr Sanderson.

#### 2) Fantasy Premier League Data Analysis (Current Project)

- Scraped data from FPL (Fantasy Premier League) API endpoints and FBref (Football statistic website)
- Cleaned data renaming columns to more understandable names.
- Created some basic data visualisations showing a players performance season by season, visualised teams' differences in strength in an spider graph.
- Summarised head-to-head performance between two teams, showing recent matches between the two teams, team performance and key players to watch.

#### 3) Calorie Tracker (with GUI)

- Created a simple calorie tracking application where the user can input and save foods with corresponding macro nutrients.
- Made a 4 pane GUI using tkinter.
- Inputted data was stored locally in a .csv file.

#### 4) Exercise & Weight Log

- Inspired by the Calorie Tracker, this project tracked Gym exercises performed (Exercise name, Weight, Rep, Set) as well as the users body weight.
- This project didn't use a GUI but a CLI for the user inputs.

Request references if needed